VIGNESH SELVARAJ

P: (425) 301-5952 | E: vignesh.io@outlook.com |

LI: www.linkedin.com/in/vigneshse | W: https://vigneshse.github.io/resume



SUMMARY

Software Development Engineer - experience in design, development, and implementation of various large-scale applications over 10 years. My specializations include Java, Spring-boot, REST APIs, Microservice & SOA Architectures and Design Patterns, Serverless Architecture using AWS, TDD and Agile SCRUM Methodology.

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Java • Spring/Spring-boot • Rest API • SOA / Microservices • Data Structures & Algorithms

EXPERIENCE

T-MOBILE | Bothell, WA

Software Engineer III

Jan 2019 - Present

This application is for Retail Store - to enhance its in-store mobility devices to be loaded with latest firmware that helps the sales reps to activate / sell the products to the walk-in customers.

- Developed cloud-ready microservices that integrates with AWS DynamoDB and S3
- Developed AWS Lambda Functions in Java
- Developed Swagger Docs based on Open API Specifications
- Developed and Contributed to an in-house Opensource Project Jazz, a serverless platform
- · Tracked features, stories, issues and tasks in Rally
- Test-driven Development with more than 80% coverage of Unit tests.
- Performed code reviews across the team.

GREAT WEST-LIFE | Toronto, ON

Senior Backend Developer

Mar 2018 - Dec 2018

Hired as a backend developer to work on a digital transformation project, developed by an agile team to help the insurance advisors, to enable sign up for new insurance term policies that integrates with various back-end systems. The application increased the efficiency of the application's sign-up process from 120 mins to 10 mins.

- Designed and implemented Spring boot RESTful Microservices for a customer-facing application, which enhances the customer experience
- Designed and developed application persistence using MongoDB and Redis Cache
- Developed Bamboo build and deployment plans to enable CI (Continuous Integration) Pipeline
- Developed event-driven REST APIs with Active MQs
- Developed Docker Images and Docker compose files
- · Tracked features, stories, issues and tasks in JIRA
- Test-driven Development with more than 80% of Unit tests using Mockito and Spring Runner frameworks.
- Performed code reviews across the team.

ROGERS COMMUNICATIONS INC | Brampton, ON

Software Development Engineer

Jun 2016 - Feb 2018

The application serves as Enterprise Service Bus (ESB), a middleware application that integrates with various back-end applications through different semantics and protocols.

- Designed and implemented enterprise-level service layer, includes both RESTful and SOAP web-services, which serves various channels include consumer, retail, and Enterprise Business Units
- Developed synchronous and asynchronous webservices using Java, Oracle SOA Suite, JMS Queues for performance and reliability
- Developed event-driven REST APIs with JMS Queues
- Developed PL/SQL Queries and Stored Procedures
- Analyzed Incidents and tickets on the Production Servers.

VIRGIN MOBILE CANADA | Toronto, ON

Software Development Engineer

Jun 2015 - Jun 2016

The application serves as a middleware between Virgin Mobile member facing front-end application and various back-end systems. The application carries out various self-serve functionalities to serve members for both prepaid and postpaid line of business.

- Designed and implemented RESTful web-service APIs for Virgin mobile app and web
- Developed Technical Detailed Design Documents based on the business requirements
- Developed service layers, and SOAP and RESTful web-services using Java/JEE
- Developed build scripts using ANT/WLST

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES | Toronto, ON

IT Analyst

Sep 2008 - Jun 2015

The application serves as a middleware between Rogers IVR front-end application and various back-end systems, carries out various self-serve functionalities to serve members without involving live agents

- Developed SOAP web-services for various IVR applications, including platform replacement project, which performs self-serve operations for consumer and business channels
- Designed and developed a service to identify the callers for IVR apps, using parallel processing and coherence caching, which improved the performance by 300% and reduced the operating cost by 56%.
- · Led and mentored a team of 6 individuals
- Developed Server-Monitoring utility using WebLogic Mbeans, which monitors the servers' state and thread; raises alert notifications, in the case of an anomaly
- Developed Socket programming to connect to the backend systems using TCP/IP in client-server architecture.

EDUCATION

VIT UNIVERSITY - VELLORE INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY | Vellore, INDIA

May 2008

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science Engineering Honors & Activities: Class Representative, Students Association